we're going to use ruby's delete
if method and the string method start
with
to delete all of the words from this
given array
that begin with s and now would be a
good time for you to take a look at the
documentation for the delete if method
and the startwith method if you're not
familiar with these
the ruby documentation tells us that
deleteif
will delete every element of the calling
array
for which the block evaluates to true
so we'll invoke delete if on our array
and each element is going to be passed
to the block
let's name this parameter word and we
know we want to
remove the element from the array if the
word begins with
s we can invoke the string
start with method
and check whether the string starts with
s
now the startwith method is going to
return a boolean either true or
false so for every word for which the
block returns true
it will be removed from the array
so let's output the array on line five
and
now we expect to see only the words that
did not begin with s
in our array
and that's what we see
now the second part of this problem says
to get rid of all words that start with
s or w so
we can change the way we write our block
on line three
and use a logical operator here
word start with s or word start with w
we expect that in our array after
running this code ice will be the only
word left
and let's run our code to see that
however there's an easier way here and
taking a close look at the documentation
for the start with method
will tell you that you can pass in
multiple prefixes as an argument to this
method
so we can pass in s and also pass in w
and our program works as expected all
the words beginning with
s or w were removed from our array